A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Real Estate, Series L FA321
Rockefeller Archive Center
- 17 West 54th Street Property
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Corporation - Scientific Housekeeping / Brides' School, 1936-1943 (Box 36, Folder 305)
    225.2
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Apartments - Cost of Construction Statement, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 306)
    Statements.
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Model Apartment, 1936-1937 (Box 36, Folder 307)
    Rockefeller Center display of model apartment; radio publicity; Nelson A. Rockefeller address.
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Apartments - Floor Plans and Photos (Box 36, Folder 308)
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Annual Reports - Mr. Staley's Reports, 1941-1944 (Box 36, Folder 309)
    Financial statements.
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Incorporation - General, 1933-1945 (Box 36, Folder 310)
    Incorporation; arrangements for meetings; sale of building; dissolution of corporation. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    225.1
    General note
    Open per KWR, 2/11/2005.
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Incorporation - Certificate of Incorporation / Bylaws, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 311)
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Incorporation - Property Transfer and Stock, 1936-1937 (Box 37, Folder 312)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. received corporation stock for property; subscribed for additional stock. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt.
    225.4
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Incorporation - Publicity, 1936-1940 (Box 37, Folder 313)
    Publicity program and plans. Correspondents include Merle Crowell, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Frank Staley.
    225.7
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Incorporation - Publicity - Newspaper Clippings, 1935-1936 (Box 37, Folder 314)
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Loan - Agreement to Make Loan, 1936-1937 (Box 37, Folder 315)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agreed to loan $1,200,000 to Corporation for construction; to be repaid when Chase Bank loans Corporation that amount on first mortgage; loan increased due to rising construction costs.
    225.8
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Loan - Loan from Chase Bank, 1936-1945 (Box 37, Folder 316)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave additional collateral to support loan; collateral returned as loan was paid off.
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Profit and Loss Statements, 1936-1939; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 37, Folder 317)
    Monthly statements; also balance sheets.
    225.10A
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Profit and Loss Statements - Balance Sheets, 1936-1941; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 37, Folder 318)
    225.109
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Profit and Loss Statements, Folder 3 of 4 (Box 37, Folder 319)
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Profit and Loss Statements, Folder 4 of 4 (Box 37, Folder 320)
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Taxes, 1937-1950 (Box 37, Folder 321)
    Assessments; payments. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
    225.13
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Sale of Apartments, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 322)
    Sale to Joseph P. Kennedy not completed.
    225.14
  - 17 West 54th Street Property - Sale of Apartments to City Bank Farmers Trust, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 323)
    Sale completed; corporation dissolved.
- Underel Holding Corporation
  - Underel Holding Corporation - General, 1929-1931; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 38, Folder 324)
    Organized for property purchases near proposed Metropolitan Opera House site; liquidated in 1951. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    157
  - Underel Holding Corporation - General, 1931-1944; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 38, Folder 325)
  - Underel Holding Corporation - General, 1942-1951; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 38, Folder 326)
  - Underel Holding Corporation - Notes, 1929-1930 (Box 38, Folder 327)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s advances to company on demand notes.
  - Underel Holding Corporation - Rockefeller Lease Revision, 1939-1944 (Box 38, Folder 328)
    Changes in Rockefeller Center lease on land.
  - Underel Holding Corporation - Minutes of Meetings, 1931-1951 (Box 38, Folder 329)
  - Underel Holding Corporation - Liquidation, 1951-1953 (Box 38, Folder 330)
    Negotiations by Rockefeller Center to liquidate Underel.
- Bishop Property
  - Bishop Property - Lease - General, 1928-1943 (Box 39, Folder 331)
    Lease of property for Rockefeller Center; purchase attempts. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    157.1
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Purchase from Mrs. Berle, 1942-1944 (Box 39, Folder 332)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased 5 parcels from Bishop estate, including land under RCA Building; copies of purchase agreements; surveys, appraisals. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, Thomas M. Debevoise, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    157.11
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Purchase from Mrs. Berle - Assignment to Underel Parcel D, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 333)
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Purchase from Mrs. Berle - Agreement with Ely and Company, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 334)
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Purchase Agreements, Surveys, Et.c, Folder 1 of 3 (Box 39, Folder 335)
    157.11A
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Purchase Agreements, Surveys, Et.c, Folder 2 of 3 (Box 39, Folder 336)
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Purchase Agreements, Surveys, Et.c, Folder 3 of 3 (Box 39, Folder 337)
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Appraisals, 1943; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 39, Folder 338)
    157.11B
  - Bishop Property - Lease - Appraisals, 1943; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 39, Folder 339)
- Washington Heights Property
  - Washington Heights Property - General, 1917-1941 (Box 40, Folder 340)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased land for use as park; World War I plan to plant vegetable gardens on land fell through. Land offered to city for park; city refused. Consideration of various plans for property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel.
    129.1
  - Washington Heights Property - Girl Scouts, Use of Property by, 1932-1933 (Box 40, Folder 341)
    Used as day camp, 1932-1933.
  - Washington Heights Property - Sale to Socony Vacuum (May 1934), 1931-1934 (Box 40, Folder 342)
    Corner lot on Broadway sold to company.
  - Washington Heights Property - Letters Regarding Reported Gift to City, 1917 (Box 40, Folder 343)
    Offer led to much controversy; city declined offer; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. denied making it.
  - Washington Heights Property - Mr. Rockefeller's Letter to Mayor, 1917 (Box 40, Folder 344)
    John D. Rockefeller Jr.'s 1917 conditions to gift; attempts to give away land.
  - Washington Heights Property - Clark Property, 1927-1938 (Box 40, Folder 345)
    Purchase not completed.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - General, 1916-1931 (Box 40, Folder 346)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. begins purchases on Heights, planning for park; title and tax problems; purchases through W. A. White and Empire Mortgage Company. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Diamond Property, 1927-1935 (Box 40, Folder 347)
    Purchased for $195,000.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Billings Property, 1926-1937 (Box 40, Folder 348)
    Use of property by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Fire.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Nolan Property (from Metropolitan Museum), 1932-1933 (Box 40, Folder 349)
    Purchased from Metropolitan Museum.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Bennett Property - Correspondence with Bennett and Stolz, 1917-1918 (Box 40, Folder 350)
    Offer to buy property declined.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Stern Property, 1930-1938 (Box 40, Folder 351)
    Purchase and transfer to city.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Lot Block 370, West of New York Central Tracks, 1933-1939 (Box 40, Folder 352)
    Purchase, gift to city.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property Purchases - Hudson River Bridge to New Jersey, 1925-1934 (Box 40, Folder 353)
    Notes on progress of bridge.
  - Washington Heights Property - Dyckman Ferry Project - General, 1918-1936 (Box 40, Folder 354)
    Purchase of property; taxes; assessments; use of land. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Washington Heights Property - Dyckman Ferry Project - Sale of Property to City, 1931-1936 (Box 40, Folder 355)
    Sold to city at assessed value.
  - Washington Heights Property - Dyckman Ferry Project - Lease for Ferry, 1916-1924 (Box 40, Folder 356)
    Arrangements for ferry docking on Rockefeller property; percentage basis, fixed rate basis. Appeals for aid from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - Washington Heights Property - Property South of Park, 1936-1941 (Box 41, Folder 357)
    Sale of extra properties not part of park; construction of apartment house on property. Approval of design by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - Washington Heights Property - Barnard - Renting - Use and Lease of Property, 1917-1935 (Box 41, Folder 358)
    Rental of barn on property to Barnard as a studio; Barnard's failure to pay rent; adjustment of rent. Barnard moves out. George G. Barnard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Washington Heights Property - Renting - General, 1917-1932 (Box 41, Folder 359)
    Rental of apartments and homes on property purchased for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. by W. A. White & Company. Lease arrangements; Paulist Choir. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Washington Heights Property - Renting - Sobol Brothers - Gasoline Station, 1930-1934 (Box 41, Folder 360)
  - Washington Heights Property - Subway Construction, 1925-1938 (Box 41, Folder 361)
    Use of Rockefeller land by subway. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - Washington Heights Property - Rock Removal - Bennett Avenue, 1917-1926 (Box 41, Folder 362)
    Rock slide along edge of Billings property; city demands Rockefeller cut back rock cliff; expensive job; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. tries to get city reimbursement, but fails. Decision to move Avenue away from cliff to eliminate danger. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, C. M. Hilton.
  - Washington Heights Property - Taxes - General, 1917-1923; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 41, Folder 363)
    Property assessments; suit to reduce assessment; reductions. Payment. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, C. M. Hilton, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Washington Heights Property - Taxes - General, 1923-1939; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 41, Folder 364)
  - Washington Heights Property - Taxes - Condemnation Proceedings and Award, 1928-1931 (Box 41, Folder 365)
    City condemned land; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. got substantial award over city's value.
  - Washington Heights Property - William A. White and Son - General, 1916-1936 (Box 41, Folder 366)
    Purchase and upkeep of property; C. M. Hilton represented White. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, C. M. Hilton, William A. White.
  - Washington Heights Property - William A. White and Son - Regarding Rent of Libby Castle, 1917-1935 (Box 42, Folder 367)
    Lease to Paulist fathers for taxes and upkeep. 1925, rental to "personality" school.
  - Washington Heights Property - William A. White and Son - Regarding Gasoline Station - Standard Oil of New York, 1919-1935 (Box 42, Folder 368)
    Texaco station replaced by Standard Oil of New York.
  - Washington Heights Property - G. C. Wheeler Photographs (Box 42, Folder 369)
  - Washington Heights Property - Miscellaneous Maps (Box 42, Folder 370)
  - miscellaneous maps from Upper West Side of New York City, near Fort Tryon (George C. Wheeler), 1915-1935; MAP (Quantity 7) (Drawer B 1, Folder 10)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Retrieval times for maps and flat files may exceed 24 hours. Individual items may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
  - Washington Heights Property - Riverside Park Development - New York Central Project, 1917-1929 (Box 42, Folder 371)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attitude toward railroad and sea plane developments along Hudson river; no action. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    129.2
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - General, 1922-1932; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 42, Folder 372)
    Landscape architect called in to plan park development; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s ideas regarding Cloisters; George G. Barnard's suggestions. Studies of park possibilities. Planning approaches to Cloisters; excess costs; satisfactory completion of work in 1935. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. Downer, Frederick Law Olmsted, George G. Barnard.
    129.3
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - General, 1932-1939; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 42, Folder 373)
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Olmsted Brothers General Correspondence, 1927-1934 (Box 42, Folder 374)
    Material from Raymond B. Fosdick office; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. has Raymond B. Fosdick make arrangements with Frederick Law Olmsted for park work; details of negotiations. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Regarding Fees and Estimates, 1927-1936 (Box 42, Folder 375)
    Material from Raymond B. Fosdick office. Adjustments due to changes; basic arguments; discussions of increased costs. Raymond B. Fosdick's investigation of costs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Frederick Law Olmsted.
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Authorizations / Decisions, 1929-1935 (Box 42, Folder 376)
    Material from Raymond B. Fosdick office; Raymond B. Fosdick and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. discussions of general program for park; financing details. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Frederick Law Olmsted.
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Memos Regarding Appropriations and Payments, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 377)
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Bill Settlement and Payment, 1932-1938 (Box 43, Folder 378)
    Adjustments of Olmsted's fee and payments. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick Law Olmsted, Jay Downer.
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Regarding Tablet, 1935-1941 (Box 43, Folder 379)
    Selection of text and style of tablets on Heights; revisions. Correspondents include Jay Downer, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Photos, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 380)
  - Washington Heights Property - Olmsted / Fort Tryon Park - Correspondence from Raymond B. Fosdick's Files, 1923-1929 (Box 43, Folder 381)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - General, 1930-1946; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 382)
    1930 arrangements for offer to city; objections to gift; negotiations over street changes. Changes; names of areas and streets; gratitude for gift. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert Moses.
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - General, 1951-1958; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 383)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Map Used in Connection with Playground Gifts (Box 43, Folder 384)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Lot 742, Plaza Widening, 1933-1941 (Box 43, Folder 385)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Letters of Gift to Mayor, 1929-1931 (Box 43, Folder 386)
    Drafts of letter to J. J. Walker.
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Statement of Cost - Fort Tryon Park and Cloister, 1938-1939 (Box 43, Folder 387)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Clippings, 1930-1932 (Box 43, Folder 388)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Regarding Deeds / Agreement, 1930-1938 (Box 44, Folder 389)
    Copy of agreement making gift.
    129.5
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Additional Gift of Land, 1932-1938 (Box 44, Folder 390)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Miscellaneous Letters from Mr. Fosdick, 1929-1937 (Box 44, Folder 391)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.-Raymond B. Fosdick correspondence re park, Cloisters Museum. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. deForest.
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Suggestions for Use of Washington Heights Property, 1922-1935 (Box 44, Folder 392)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Dedication - Mr. Rockefeller's Address, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 393)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Appreciation Letters - General, 1930-1954 (Box 44, Folder 394)
  - Washington Heights Property - Gift to City - Letters of Appreciation from Children, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 395)
  - Washington Heights Property - Fort Tryon Park - Maps Regarding Gift (Box 44, Folder 396)
  - Washington Heights Property - Playground Fort Washington Avenue - General, 1935-1941 (Box 44, Folder 397)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives additional land for use as playground; negotiations with city; gratitude. Use of playground to protect park proper from overuse; area leased to city, then given outright, 1941. Correspondents include Jay Downer, Robert Moses, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    129.6
  - Washington Heights Property - Playground Fort Washington Avenue - Regarding Lot 600 Lease, 1935-1944 (Box 44, Folder 398)
    Additional land south of park leased to city as playground; later deeded to city.
- Conpo Realty Company
  - Conpo Realty Company - General, 1950-1959 (Box 44, Folder 399)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchases property behind Philipsberg Manor to protect the historic site. Problems with demolishing dwellings during housing shortage. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. J. Yates, Phillip Keebler.
    266